Tingzhen Dong

■ dongtz2020@mail.sustech.edu.cn | 🎓 rogerdtz.github.io | 🖸 github.com/RogerDTZ

I am interested in architecture, operating systems, and cloud computing. My recent research focuses on efficient defense against speculative execution and measured boot in confidential cloud computing. I desire to bring about innovations in architecture and system disciplines.

Education

Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT)

Boston, U.S.

Visiting Student, CSAIL, Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (EECS)

Mar 2023 - Aug 2023

- · Interned at Arch-Sec Lab
- Course attended: 6.S983 Secure Hardware Design

Southern University of Science and Technology (SUSTech)

Shenzhen, China

Undergraduate, Computer Science and Technology (CST)

Sept 2020 - Current

- GPA: 3.89/4.0, Rank: 6/221
- Student of 2020 Turing Class

Research Experiences

Arch-Sec Lab, CSAIL, EECS, MIT

Supervisor: Mengjia Yan

Mar 2023 - Aug 2023

- Led a project protecting constant-time programs against transient attacks that leak secrets.
- Relieved the hardware complexity with static and coarse granularity labels as well as hardware-software co-design.
- Designed an ahead-of-time analysis framework that automates the rearrangement of the stack layout of binary.
- Keywords: Computer Architecture, CPU Simulation, Speculative Execution, Binary Analysis, Gem5, Valgrind

Teecert Labs, CST, SUSTech

Supervisor: Yinqian Zhang

Sept 2021 - Current

- Led a project of designing a framework provisioning confidential virtual trusted platform modules (TPM) for virtual machines (VM) in the cloud.
- · Designed an encrypted protocol for TPM commands traveling through the untrusted hypervisor.
- Adapted OVMF (UEFI for VM) for backend attestation and channel establishment.
- Developed a kernel module encapsulating raw commands from intrinsic TPM drivers into encrypted ones.
- Keywords: Virtualization, AMD SEV-SNP, Measured Boot, TPM Protocols and Emulators, Linux Kernel, QEMU, UEFI (OVMF)

Highlighted Course Projects

PotatOS

Operating System (CS334), Instructor: Yinqian Zhang

July 2022

- Operating system from scratch, with support of SMP, based on C++.
- Preemptive resource management: Pages and processes are held and stolen by CPUs.
- User mode: musl libc is integrated. System calls in POSIX semantics are proxied by the PotatOS runtime library.
- Hardware abstraction layer: PotatOS decouples hardware-level code and operating system code.
- Self-designed memory layout, memory initialization, and trap mechanism.
- Integrated Microsoft mimalloc for efficient kernel memory allocation.
- Keywords Operating system from scratch, SMP

Hive CPU

Computer Organization (CS214), Instructor: Jin Zhang

May 2022 - June 2022

- · Asynchronous pipeline CPU on FPGA
- ISA: Mips32r6el
- Register renaming implemented.
- Dynamic overclocking implemented.
- Established compiler toolchain for C++. Snake game programmed by C++ could run on Hive.
- **Keywords:** CPU, FPGA, Asynchronous pipeline, Cross-compilation

Yet Another Address Sanitizer

Computer Security (CS315), Instructor: Fengwei Zhang

Oct 2021 - Jan 202

- · LLVM-based instrumentation plugin guaranteeing memory access sanity.
- Proposed and addressed buffer overflow cases that cannot be detected by existing solutions such as ASan.
- Light-weight implementation based on pointer arithmetic checking and tagged pointers.
- Keywords: Compilers, LLVM Pass, Buffer overflow detection, Pointer tagging

November 5, 2023

AlphaReversi Zero

Artificial Intelligence (CS311), Instructor: Bo Yuan

- Reinforcement learning AI for Reversed-Reversi, imitating AlphaGo Zero.
- Self-implemented neural network and training. No dependency on machine learning frameworks such as PyTorch.
- · Accelerated self-play simulation using self-implemented distributed computing.
- Keywords: Artificial Intelligence, AlphaGo Zero, Neural Network, Distributed computing

Extracurricular Experiences

SUSTech Collegiate Programming Team

Leader Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

- 7 years of experience in Olympiad in Informatics (OI) + 2 years of experience in Collegiate Programming Contest (ICPC)
- · Organized routine training, maintained disciplines, and promoted team culture construction.

The 4th Southern University of Science and Technology Collegiate Programming Contest

Shenzhen, China

Dec 2021

July 2022

Director

Polished online judge's front end and back end for amenity.

- Configured, deployed, and maintained online judge's server and judgehost cluster.
- Composed questions for the contest.
- Designed the contest schedule.
- More than 250 students in SUSTech attended the contest. More than 200 teams from Chinese colleges attended the contest online.
- The contest received official sponsorship from a local IT company.

6.S983 - Secure Hardware Design, MIT

Boston, U.S.

Lab Tester Mar 2023 - May 2023

- Tested Rowhammer lab, ASLR Bypassing lab, and CPU fuzzing lab before they were published.
- Provided difficulty estimations and document improvement suggestions.
- Discovered bugs in the fancy CPU when it was adapted for the fuzzing lab.

CS208 - Algorithm Design and Analysis, SUSTech

Shenzhen, China

Student Assistant Feb 2022 - June 2022, Sept 2022 - Jan 2023

- Piloted the composition of 50 programming questions for the course's 13 labs.
- Communicated with the teaching assistant and students to tune the teaching pace.

CS203 - Data Structures and Algorithm Analysis, SUSTech

Shenzhen, China

Sept 2022 - Jan 2023, Sept 2023 - Current

Student Assistant

• Composed 7 lab questions about balanced binary search tree in 2022 fall.

• Hosted lab tutorials mentoring 40 students in 2023 fall.

CS303 - Artificial Intelligence, SUSTech

Shenzhen, China

Student Assistant

Sept 2022 - Jan 2023

Lab Q&A

· Instructed and deployed course projects.

Anki-Android

Contributor Apr 2022 - May 2022

- Added support for hierarchy tag (PR #10966).
- Eulogized by several maintainers for quick responses and good coding style.

Achievements

Nov 2022 2nd Place , IndySCC22 Student Cluster Competition	Online
Apr 2022 Gold Medal 7/166 , The 2021 International Collegiate Programming Contest Asia Macau Regional Contest	Online
Nov 2021 Gold Medal 22/682 , The 2021 International Collegiate Programming Contest Asia Shanghai Regional Contest	Online
May 2021 Silver Medal 7/49 , The 2020 International Collegiate Programming Contest Asia Macau Regional Contest	Macau, China
Apr 2021 Gold Medal 13/294 , The 2020 International Collegiate Programming Contest Asia-East Continent Final	Xi'an, China
Dec 2020 Gold Medal 19/677 , The 2020 International Collegiate Programming Contest Asia Shanghai Regional Contest	Online
Nov 2020 Gold Medal 12/324 , The 2020 China Collegiate Programming Contest Changchun Regional Contest	Online

Skills

Programming C/C++, Java, Python

Miscellaneous Vim (good proficiency, 8 years of experience), Shell, Git

Sports Skilled in tennis, swimming, middle and long-distance running

November 5, 2023 2